Mitisha Shah

902, Yash apartment, Opposite Gowalia Tank Jain Temple, A.K.Marg, Mumbai, 400026, +91 9820494904, miti.shah98@gmail.com

DATE OF BIRTH: 05/05/1998 NATIONALITY: Indian

LINKS

LinkedIn

PROFILE

Dedicated and passionate Physiotherapist with experience in various fields of physiotherapy during the graduation tenure. Also, extensive 1 year experience with Cancer Rehabilitation among cancer patient, adept in properly diagnosing and framing the treatment strategy undue the pressure. Bringing forth an empathetic and professional attitude when counseling patient on preventive care and achieving a positive lifestyle. Committed in utilizing my skills to help others, while working for the society.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

SEPT 2021 - PRESENT

Onco-physiotherapist at Tata Memorial Hospital, Parel, Mumbai

- Participated in Quality Management and Performance enhancing activities in patients along with counselling them to have a positive attitude towards life.
- Have had good experience with lymph oedema Management in Post-operative patients.
- Worked in collaboration with Physicians and Case Supervisors to create effective treatment programs for patients.
- Worked to educate and treat patients with respiratory issues.

APR 2022—PRESENT

Physiotherapist, Multiple Sclerosis society of India, Sion, Mumbai

- Diagnosing Rehabilitating patients with multiple sclerosis according to stage and symptoms.
- Psychological counselling along with rehab to have an effective prognosis.
- Providing appropriate ergonomic advice to the patients considering their status and position.

JUNE 2021 --- SEPT 2021

Clinical practice as Physiotherapist at a private orthopedic clinic setup, Mumbai

- Active coordination with the orthopaedic surgeon regarding the prognosis and management strategies of the patients.
- Dealt with variety of diagnosis and management with modern technologies and evidence-based practice.
- Provided follow-up care for patients.
- Developed trusting relationships with patients and families.

NOV 2020 — MAY 2021

Physiotherapist Intern at Pravara Institute of Medical Sciences, Loni, Ahmednagar

• History taking and physical examination of patients and probable diagnosis and further

investigations. Set individually tailored protocols with regard to the patients' conditions.

- Rehabilitation experience including assessment and rehabilitation of individuals in the spinal cord rehabilitation Centre of Dr. A.P. J Abdul Kalam College of Physiotherapy.
- Experience in ICU management including bronchial hygiene care, Neuro and Pediatric ICU.
- Pulmonary Rehabilitation and Cardiac Rehabilitation for all respiratory and cardiac conditions along with various comorbidity management.

JULY 2019

Volunteer at Parkinson's Disease and Movement Disorder Society

Assisting people with Parkinson's with physiotherapy and other extra-curricular group activities.

PROJECTS

NOV 2020 — MAY 2021

Research Project, Dr.A.P.J. Abdul Kalam College of Physiotherapy, Loni

- Effects of group based low intensity exercise along with Mitchell's relaxation on fatigue, sleep quality and self-esteem
- Sciatica: Treatment with a blend of Maitland Mobilization, McKenzie exercise along with NMES – A Case Study (Published)

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

AUG 2016—OCT 2020 Bachelor of Physiotherapy (BPTh) at Pravara Institute of Medical Sciences, Loni

Apart from Academics, active participant, and organizer for various cultural and sports

activities during the course tenure.

JULY 2014 — APR 2016 Higher Secondary Education at K.C. College, Churchgate

With Science and Information Technology as my majors

JUNE 2000 — MAR 2014 Alma mater from Walsingham House School, Nepeansea Road, Mumbai

SKILLS

Ability to Work in a Team Expert Fast Learner Expert

Ability to work under pressure Expert Communication Skills Expert

HOBBIES

Basketball, Reading, Adventurous activities, Classical dance

REFERENCES

Dr. Aashirwad Mahajan (PT)

Associate professor of Cardiorespiratory Physiotherapy

Dr. A.P.J.Abdul Kalam College of Physiotherapy

aashirwad.mahajan@gmail.com

Dr. Deepali Hande (PT)

Professor of Community Physiotherapy and Head of Department

Dr. A.P.J.Abdul Kalam College of Physiotherapy

deepalihande28@gmail.com